clubrunner.ca 2018-08-13

# Privacy Policy | ClubRunner

**Last Updated: May 9, 2018**

**At ClubRunner, we're committed to protecting your privacy. This Privacy Policy explains how we collect, use, and disclose information processed through this website, and our online subscription service (the "Services").  **

This page sets out our privacy policy and describes why and how we collect, use and disclose personal information which you choose to provide to us on our website, as well as how to access, modify, or delete your personal information. This policy doesn't apply to anyone who isn't under our control or management, such as the operators of other websites that you might link to from our website. Such operators may have their own privacy policies, which might differ from ours.

### **How Will We Collect Personal Information?**

You are under no obligation to disclose any personal information to us at any time. We collect information you provide directly to us. For example, whenever you participate in any interactive features of the Services such as filling out a form, requesting customer support, sending us an email, or calling us.  In the process you may be asked to give your name, e-mail address, mailing address, and any other information you choose to provide for the purpose of these Services. We or a designated third party may collect payment and credit card information when you subscribe to our paid Services or purchase additional services.

Information We Collect Automatically When You Use Our Services

When you access or use our Services, we may automatically collect information about you, including:

  * Log Information: We log information about your use of the Services, including the type of browser you use, access times, pages viewed, your IP address, your general location, and the page you visited before navigating to our Services.
  * Device Information: We collect information about the computer or mobile device you use to access our Services, including the hardware model, operating system and version.
  * Cookies: We use cookies to store your login session and other information to make your navigation of our Services easier. More information on cookies is available below.

**Use of Cookies and Other Tracking Technologies**

Our site uses "cookies" which are small files containing pieces of information that are stored by your browser on your computer's hard drive. Most Web browsers automatically accept cookies, but if you prefer, you can set your browser to block them. Our cookies can contain information such as your user ID that our website uses to recognize you. Our cookies can't read data off your hard disk or read cookie files created by other sites. The only personal information our cookies contain is the information you provide yourself. When you enter personal information on our website, your personal information will be linked to the cookie we save on your computer. If you do choose to delete your cookie, you may not be able to use the administrative features of the website.

We use Google Analytics to track how visitors interact with our website, analyze where traffic is generated from and collect information related to general site engagement.

Third party advertising management services such as Google and Facebook may display tailored messages upon you interacting with our website through the use of cookies. You can opt out of these ads at any time when displayed. For more information on Google Ads, [click here](https://support.google.com/ads/answer/2662922?hl=en). For more information on opting out of ads on Facebook, [click here](https://www.facebook.com/help/146952742043748). Should you delete your cookies, please note, you will need to opt out of seeing these messages again. These cookies cannot personally identify you and expire after 180 days or until you clear your cookies.

On customer websites, where you engage with social share buttons (ex: Facebook Like Button or the share content buttons), the services that manage the social platform you get directed to may use cookies. ClubRunner is not affiliated with any of these services and all legalities surrounding the use of cookies are thus under the policies set by the social media platforms.

### **How Do We Use  Personal Information?**

We may use information about you for various purposes, including to:

  * Provide, maintain, customize, and improve our Services;
  * Provide and deliver the products and services you request, process transactions and send you related information, including confirmations and invoices,
  * Send you technical notices, updates, security alerts and support and administrative messages;
  * Respond to your comments, questions and requests and provide customer service;
  * Communicate with you about products, services, offers, promotions, and events offered by ClubRunner and others, and provide news and information we think will be of interest to you;
  * Monitor and analyze trends, usage and activities in connection with our Services; and
  * Carry out any other purpose for which the information was collected.

You may receive automatically-generated emails from ClubRunner that are triggered when you perform certain tasks such as registering for an event, volunteering for a task, subscribing to a bulletin, or requesting a forgotten password.

You may also receive emails from other club members. ClubRunner does not control the frequency or content of member-generated emails. You have the option to unsubscribe from receiving these emails by either updating your communication preferences from within your profile, or removing your email address entirely.

### **How Is Your Personal Information Protected?**

ClubRunner is committed to protecting your personal information and has developed policies and procedures to ensure our compliance with our own Security and Privacy Policy and with applicable International laws.

We also understand your concerns about online security and take reasonable measures to help protect information about you from loss, theft, misuse and unauthorized access, disclosure, alteration and destruction. 

### **How Do We Disclose or Share Your Information?**

When you voluntarily provide ClubRunner with personally identifiable information online, that information is kept within the ClubRunner family of web site(s) and will not be sold, rented or otherwise traded to any third party.

We may share your information as follows or as otherwise described in this Privacy Policy:

  * With vendors, consultants, and other service providers who need access to such information to carry out work on our behalf;
  * In response to a request for information if we believe disclosure is in accordance with any applicable law, rule or regulation;
  * If we believe your actions are inconsistent with the spirit or language of our user agreements or policies, or to protect the rights, property and safety of ClubRunner or others;
  * With your consent or at your direction.

We may also share aggregated or de-identified information, which cannot reasonably be used to identify you.

**Sub-Processors**

ClubRunner employs other companies and people to provide functions that form part of our Services, for example, email sending, social media sharing, payment processing, help desk software, etc. ClubRunner has made and continues to make efforts to ensure all its sub-processors comply with our privacy policies. For a list of ClubRunner's sub-processors, please email us at support@clubrunner.ca.

**Data Retention**

We will retain your personal information only for as long as it is needed to provide our Services, and this depends on the purposes for which we use it, unless applicable law requires we either dispose of it or keep it longer. We may also continue to store your personal information to allow us to resolve disputes, enforce our agreements, comply with legal obligations and/or for other legally permissible purposes consistent with this Privacy Policy.

### **How to View,  Update or Delete Your Personal Information**

You may, at any time, view, update and request to permanently delete any of your personal information. These tools are made available to all Site Administrators, or you may contact ClubRunner at support@clubrunner.ca.

Upon request, ClubRunner will provide you with information about whether we hold any of your personal information. If you provide us with your personal information, you have the following rights:

  * To review the personal information we have stored;
  * To request that we correct any errors, outdated information, or omissions;
  * To unsubscribe from being contacted by us; and
  * To have your information permanently deleted.

We will respond to your request within a reasonable timeframe and notify you of the action we have taken.

### **Questions Regarding This Privacy Policy**

If you have any questions please contact ClubRunner, 2060 Winston Park Drive, Suite 102, Oakville, Ontario, L6H 5R7. You may call us at (905) 829-5299, or email us at support@clubrunner.ca.

### **Changes To This Privacy Policy**

We may change this Privacy Policy from time to time. If we make changes, we will notify you by revising the date at the top of the policy and, in some cases, we may provide you with additional notice, such as adding a statement to our home page or sending an email. We encourage you to review the Privacy Policy whenever you access the Services or otherwise interact with us to stay informed about our information practices.

### **Note On Jurisdiction**

ClubRunner is a privately held Canadian company with headquarters in Oakville, Ontario, Canada. Consequently, by using our Services you agree that in all matters relating to this web site(s) you shall be governed by the laws of the province of Ontario or Canada, as applicable, and further, that you submit to the jurisdiction of the courts of the province of Ontario.

You may not use our Services if law prohibits you from doing so in the country in which you reside.
